Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
Hey Erika, how are you today?
嘿Erika，你今天怎么样？
Marco, I'm doing really well and I'm really looking forward to today's lesson.
Marco，我很好，而且我很期待今天的课程。
Well so am I because here at EnglishPod we're giving you real English.
我也是，因为在EnglishPod我们给你真正的英语。
Everyday English.
日常英语。
Exactly, English that you hear in movies or in TV shows.
没错，你在电影或电视节目里听到的英语。
This is English people actually use.
这是人们实际使用的英语。
So Erika, what is our topic for today?
那么Erika，我们今天的话题是什么？
Well today we're talking about computer viruses.
今天我们讨论电脑病毒。
Perfect, so I think it's time for us to take a look at our preview.
太好了，我想是时候看看我们的预览了。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, today we've got two words to preview.
好的，今天我们要预览两个词。
The first word is virus.
第一个词是病毒。
Virus.
病毒。
So, if your computer has a computer virus, it means your computer is sick, right?
所以，如果你的电脑有电脑病毒，意味着你的电脑生病了，对吧？
Actually a computer virus is a program that is designed to harm or to damage your computer.
实际上，电脑病毒是一种旨在伤害或损坏你电脑的程序。
Oh I see, okay.
哦，我明白了，好的。
Well, thank you for being so technical.
嗯，谢谢你这么专业。
That's the technical explanation.
这是专业的解释。
Okay, let's take a look at our second word for our preview today and that would be froze.
好的，我们来看看今天预览的第二个词，那就是死机。
Froze.
死机。
So, if your computer froze, it means that...
所以，如果你的电脑死机了，意思是……
Your computer stopped working.
你的电脑停止工作了。
Your applications or your programs stopped working and you just can't do anything.
你的应用程序或程序停止工作，你什么都做不了。
Your computer is broken.
你的电脑坏了。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So, let's listen to our dialogue.
那么，我们来听对话。
It's going to be a little bit fast but...
可能会有点快，但是……
Don't worry if you don't understand everything.
如果你没全听懂，别担心。
At the end of this podcast, you'll understand everything.
在这个播客结束时，你会全部理解的。
Perfect, let's listen.
完美，我们来听吧。
Oh great, the stupid computer froze again.
哦天哪，这破电脑又死机了。
It's the third time today.
今天第三次了。
Hey Samuel, can you come take a look at my PC?
嘿Samuel，你能来看看我的电脑吗？
It's acting up again.
它又出毛病了。
It must have a virus or something.
一定是中了病毒之类的。
Just give me a second, I'll be right up.
稍等一下，我马上上来。
I ran a virus scan on your computer and it turns out that you have a lot of infected
我在你的电脑上运行了病毒扫描，结果发现有很多受感染的
files.
文件。
But I'm quite careful when I'm browsing the internet.
但我上网时很小心啊。
I have no idea how I could have picked up a virus.
我完全不知道怎么会染上病毒。
Well, you have to make sure their antivirus software is updated regularly.
嗯，你得确保杀毒软件定期更新。
Yours wasn't up to date.
你的杀毒软件没有更新。
That's probably what was causing your problems.
这很可能就是导致你电脑出问题的原因。
Okay, anything else?
好的，还有别的吗？
Yeah, try not to kick or hit the computer.
有，尽量别踢或打电脑。
Um, yeah, sorry about that.
呃，嗯，抱歉。
Well I completely understand this guy.
我完全理解这家伙。
When my computer freezes, I kick it and punch it and do everything to it.
我的电脑死机时，我又踢又打，什么都干得出来。
I hope you don't punch it too hard, Marco.
希望你别打得太狠，马可。
Well it's still working so it's alright.
嗯，它还能用，所以没事。
Okay.
好的。
Alright, let's take a look at our language takeaway.
好了，我们来看看今天的语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
In today's language takeaway, we have two words.
今天的语言要点有两个词。
The first word for today is infected file.
今天的第一个词是受感染的文件。
Infected file.
受感染的文件。
And what is an infected file?
什么是受感染的文件？
An infected file is a file in your computer that has a virus in it.
受感染的文件就是电脑里带有病毒的文件。
Ah, perfect.
啊，完美。
That's really clear.
解释得很清楚。
What is our second word for the language takeaway today?
今天语言要点的第二个词是什么？
Our second word is not up to date.
第二个词是未更新。
Not up to date.
未更新。
And what is it when something is not up to date?
那什么东西未更新是什么意思？
It means it doesn't have all the most recent information.
意思是它没有包含所有最新的信息。
Okay, perfect.
好的，完美。
Now let's listen to some examples.
现在我们来听一些例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I need to buy a new computer because mine isn't up to date.
我需要买台新电脑，因为我的电脑已经过时了。
Example two.
例子二。
I can't find the street.
我找不到那条街。
Are you sure this map is up to date?
你确定这张地图是最新的吗？
Example three.
例子三。
Sarah has just finished the reports and all the information is up to date.
莎拉刚刚完成了报告，所有信息都是最新的。
Okay, that was pretty clear.
好的，这很清楚。
You know, you can also use this phrase positively.
你知道吗，你也可以正面使用这个短语。
You can say up to date.
你可以说 up to date。
Okay, for example, we can say this is a new map.
好的，例如，我们可以说这是一张新地图。
This is the most up to date map.
这是最新的地图。
Exactly.
没错。
Or if I bought a new computer, I could say I just got a new computer.
或者如果我买了一台新电脑，我可以说我刚买了一台新电脑。
All my software is up to date.
我所有的软件都是最新的。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So now let's take a look at some phrases.
现在让我们来看一些短语。
And it's time for putting it all together.
现在是综合运用的时候了。
Putting it together.
综合运用。
Okay, so Samuel said a really great phrase.
好的，塞缪尔说了一个非常好的短语。
He said, I'll be right up.
他说，我马上上来。
I'll be right up.
我马上上来。
Now, we can use this phrase in a lot of different situations.
这个短语可以用在很多不同的场合。
So let's listen to some examples.
让我们听一些例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Can you help me with my computer?
你能帮我看看我的电脑吗？
I'll be right there.
我马上到。
Example two.
例子二。
Come downstairs.
下楼来。
Dinner is ready.
晚饭准备好了。
I'll be right down.
我马上下来。
Example three.
例子三。
Hurry up.
快点。
I need to use the bathroom.
我要用洗手间。
I'll be right out.
我马上出来。
Okay, really great and clear examples, right?
好的，非常棒且清晰的例子，对吧？
Yeah, you know that phrase, I'll be right out.
是的，你知道那个短语，我马上出来。
I used to hear this all the time when I was young.
我小时候经常听到这个。
Really?
真的吗？
How come?
为什么？
Well, I have two sisters and we were always fighting for the bathroom.
嗯，我有两个姐姐，我们总是抢洗手间。
So someone was always saying, just a minute, I'll be right out.
所以总有人说，等一下，我马上出来。
Ah, yes, that's common.
啊，是的，这很常见。
I had that too when I was young.
我年轻时也遇到过。
Okay, now our second phrase is, it turns out that.
好了，现在我们的第二个短语是，结果发现。
It turns out that.
结果发现。
This is a great phrase.
这个短语很棒。
You can use it in many different situations.
你可以在很多不同的场合使用它。
Marco, can you give us an example?
马可，能给我们举个例子吗？
Sure.
当然。
For example, I can say, Frank didn't come to work today and it turns out that he was
比如，我可以说，弗兰克今天没来上班，结果发现他
sick.
生病了。
Yep.
是的。
Or I could say, oh, I've been feeling really sick recently.
或者我可以说，哦，我最近一直觉得很不舒服。
Why?
为什么？
It turns out that I'm pregnant.
结果发现我怀孕了。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
Are you really pregnant?
你真的怀孕了吗？
No, I'm not.
不，我没有。
I'm just kidding.
我只是开玩笑。
All right.
好吧。
So it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again, but this time it'll be a little bit
现在让我们再听一遍对话，但这次会稍微
slower.
慢一点。
All right.
好的。
Oh great.
哦，太好了。
This stupid computer froze again.
这台破电脑又死机了。
That's the third time today.
这已经是今天第三次了。
Hey Samuel, can you come take a look at my PC?
嘿，塞缪尔，能过来看看我的电脑吗？
It's acting up again.
它又出毛病了。
It must have a virus or something.
肯定是中病毒了之类的。
Just give me a second.
稍等一下。
I'll be right up.
我马上上来。
I ran a virus scan on your computer and it turns out that you have a lot of infected
我给你的电脑做了病毒扫描，结果发现有很多受感染的
files.
文件。
But I'm quite careful when I'm browsing the internet.
但我上网时很小心啊。
I have no idea how I could have picked up a virus.
真不知道怎么会染上病毒。
Well, you have to make sure that your antivirus software is updated regularly.
嗯，你得确保你的杀毒软件定期更新。
Yours wasn't up to date.
你的杀毒软件不是最新的。
It's probably what was causing your problems.
这很可能就是问题的原因。
Okay.
好的。
Anything else?
还有别的吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
Try not to kick or hit the computer.
尽量不要踢或打电脑。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Okay.
好的。
That was a lot more clear this time.
这次清楚多了。
Definitely.
确实。
Yeah.
嗯。
I understood a lot more.
我理解得更多了。
Okay.
好的。
So now it's time to look at Fluency Builder.
现在该看看流利度构建器了。
Erika, why don't you explain what Fluency Builder is?
Erika，你来解释一下什么是流利度构建器吧？
In Fluency Builder, we give you some great useful phrases to help you express your ideas
在流利度构建器中，我们提供一些很棒的有用短语，帮助你清晰地表达想法。
clearly.
清晰地。
Okay, great.
好的，太棒了。
So let's look at Fluency Builder.
那我们来看看流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay.
好的。
So in this dialogue, we know his computer wasn't working.
在这个对话中，我们知道他的电脑坏了。
Right.
对。
So many students would probably say his computer was acting strangely.
很多学生可能会说他的电脑行为异常。
His computer isn't working properly.
他的电脑不能正常工作了。
Exactly.
没错。
And that's perfect and that's fine.
那样说完全没问题。
Yeah.
嗯。
But there's a really great way to say it that we heard in the dialogue.
但我们在对话中听到了一种非常好的表达方式。
It's acting up again.
它又出毛病了。
I love this phrase.
我喜欢这个短语。
It's acting up.
它出毛病了。
Yeah.
嗯。
It just sounds really natural.
听起来很自然。
It sounds really natural.
Okay.
好的。
We're going to listen to our dialogue a third time, but this time it'll be at the normal
我们将第三次听对话，但这次是正常语速。
speed.
速度。
Try and see if you can hear these key words.
试着看看你能不能听到这些关键词。
Oh, great.
哦，太好了。
The stupid computer froze again.
那破电脑又死机了。
It's the third time today.
今天已经是第三次了。
Hey, Samuel.
嘿，塞缪尔。
Can you come take a look at my PC?
你能过来看看我的电脑吗？
It's acting up again.
它又开始出毛病了。
It must have a virus or something.
肯定是中病毒了还是怎么的。
Just give me a second.
稍等一下。
I'll be right up.
我马上上来。
I ran a virus scan on your computer and it turns out that you have a lot of infected
我在你电脑上运行了病毒扫描，结果发现你有很多受感染的
files.
文件。
But I'm quite careful when I'm browsing the internet.
但我上网的时候挺小心的。
I have no idea how I could have picked up a virus.
我不知道怎么会染上病毒。
Well, you have to make sure their antivirus software is updated regularly.
嗯，你得确保杀毒软件定期更新。
Yours wasn't up to date.
你的杀毒软件不是最新的。
That's probably what was causing your problems.
这很可能就是导致你出问题的原因。
Okay.
好吧。
Anything else?
还有别的吗？
Yeah.
有。
Try not to kick or hit the computer.
尽量别踢或打电脑。
Yeah.
嗯。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
So Marco, I really think that my computer actually has a virus now.
所以马可，我真的觉得我的电脑现在中病毒了。
Really?
真的吗？
How come?
怎么回事？
I've been turning on my computer and then suddenly it turns off by itself.
我每次打开电脑，它就会突然自己关机。
It shuts down by itself.
它自己关机。
Yeah.
对。
That sounds like a virus.
听起来像是病毒。
But I ran a virus scan and there was no problem.
但我运行了病毒扫描，没发现问题。
Well, maybe your antivirus software isn't up to date.
嗯，也许你的杀毒软件不是最新的。
Yeah.
对。
I guess I'd better call Samuel.
我想我最好给塞缪尔打个电话。
Yeah.
对。
You can call Samuel to fix it.
你可以叫塞缪尔来修。
Yeah.
对。
All right, folks.
好了，各位。
We're out of time now, but be sure to go to our website at EnglishPod.com where you can
我们时间到了，但一定要去我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在那里你可以
leave all your questions and comments.
留下所有问题和评论。
So stay tuned for our next great lesson.
请继续关注我们的下一堂精彩课程。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。